DAVID RADJAI

Software Engineer

FTL, FL, EST | P: (954) 554-3162 | dradjaidev@gmail.com | linkedin.com/davidradjai | github.com/dradjai

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with proficiency in Java, SQL, Spring Boot, Angular, Javascript, React and MERN. My recent projects include a mortgage resource platform that takes user requests and includes a mortgage calculator, and a banking application that handles bank transactions. 15+ years of experience in the mortgage industry, being able to close \$800,000 in my first 3 months.

EDUCATION

BOCA CODE, Software Engineering Career Course (2023)
COGENT UNIVERSITY, Full Stack Java Development Course (2022)
NOVA SOUTHEASTERN UNIVERSITY, MS in Information Technology (2022)
NOVA SOUTHEASTERN UNIVERSITY, MS in Business Information (2012)

Boca Raton, FL

Boca Raton, FL

Davie, FL

Davie, FL

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript | Core Java | Typescript | HTML | CSS | SQL (MySQL)

Technologies: React | Angular | Express | Spring Boot | Spring JPA | Spring Core | Hibernate | AWS | GCP

PROJECTS

THE MORTGAGE ZONE - WEB BASED APP REPO | LIVE

2023

- Developed a web-based application utilizing **MERN** STACK to create a comprehensive mortgage resource platform where users can add, edit and delete scenario requests. **Javascript, React, Express, Node.js, AWS, MongoDB, GCP.**
- Integrated a mortgage calculator into the application, providing users with an accurate tool to calculate mortgage payments.
- Developed a database of brokers, enabling users to access comprehensive information about various mortgage professionals.

BANKING APPLICATION, (Team Project) - WEB BASED APP

2022

- Created a system that handles bank transactions with minimal effort, allowing users to view their accounts and perform functions such as deposits, withdrawals, and transfers.
- Worked as a Full-Stack Java Developer on a team project of 4 engineers for a banking application
- Utilized technologies such as Java, MySQL, Spring Boot, JWT, Apache Tomcat, HTML, CSS, Typescript, and Angular 11 to develop the application.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX/UI MERN Intern Developer at Boca Code

Boca Raton, FL - June 2023 - Present

- UX/UI focused. Creating a portfolio with anime and Generative AI Images using Tailwind CSS, Typescript, and Next JS.
- Collaborating in an Agile/Scrum methodology with weekly stand-up meetings with a team of 10+ engineers.
- Converting Figma mockups into interactive and responsive web applications, ensuring seamless user experience across
 devices and screen sizes.

MORTGAGE UNDERWRITER at Caliber Home Loans

Remote - Based in Coppell, TX, Nov 2020 - Apr 2022

- Conducted risk assessments and implemented risk mitigation strategies, resulting in a low default rate of less than 1%.
 Resulting in being top 20% in a team of 15+ mortgage underwriters.
- Demonstrated strong judgment and data analysis skills by conducting comprehensive research and analyzing complex loan review for 10% of loan monthly, resulting in informed decision-making and accurate loan evaluations.

BRANCH COORDINATOR & APPROVAL SPECIALIST at Priority Lending Plantation, FL, Feb 2019 – Oct 2020

- Achieved consistently low fallout rates through diligent loan reviews and proactive problem-solving, contributing to improved operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.
- Consulted and offered valuable insights and recommendations on real estate tech solutions, such as Jungo: The Mortgage
 app, resulting in the successful implementation of a new CRM platform, increasing team efficiency by 25% and improving
 client relationship management

MORTGAGE PROFESSIONAL at JP Morgan Chase, Finance of America & Americas Mortgage Professionals 2009 – 2019

- Successfully closed \$800,000 in residential mortgage loans within the first 3 months of tenure resulting in exceeding sales targets and demonstrating exceptional performance.
- Developed the Purchase Funding Department and oversaw 3 employees. Led team to fund over 20 mil in the first month.
- Worked on a successful 6-month loan modification project, meeting goals and achieving results. Recognized by management for exceptional performance. Transitioned to Purchase Funding Department based on performance once project completed.